Hello, everyone thanks for coming I'm a silicon I'm a
...program manager in the big data team
in as your time join here with tim I'm tim bedrock I'm a
technical evangelist based out of chicago so thanks everyone for coming I know it's six thirty
in the evening and having some amazing session throw diving attending as well and I know
there's a party right after this so I really appreciate people who came
The...itself isbig data and actually there's a lot to cover normally like at
this big data has lot-of technologies in there and v coverage in like
...for sessions.
And, I was I was telling
the that organizer like oy so I have one-hour to cover and you're like, yeah,
don't worry that people who come for build has really high iq and I said
mom I can by that?
So, if I stream through the dec...you don't understand
the demo then you don't fit in his definition but...just following
his definition so what I have is like literally like seven eight slides in this
...to set of the context and the idea is that we go
and build actual apps end-to-end over here?
And, the and the daggers...literally have not go into too much
depth and there are some topics I will just mention but, I will try to covered most of the
ones which we will using the demo itself okay so...that get started.
I think this is like there's a variable do the check in terms of like maybe I'm just.
Visiting my thirty seconds because we've already noise so how many people are familiar with the
with big data...do this whole ecosystem...using it.
Ogre...spend thirty seconds so,
basically the question is like why do we care about the big data right so
like data has been there forever and there have been some awesome technologies both build
...microsoft and out and, other companies which is like whether
it is relational store or whether it is like for biif
annals a analytics for each dl so what
...what changed and why suddenly there
is so much hype around like a big data and all of that I think it is less about like
it's not just about like what you want to goal and do with the data I
think like that the primary thing that changes the type of the data and how it
is being generated so of course the volume
changed like now everyone wants to send some
...somewhere and, producing lots and lots of data and it is also about
...the speed the data is being produced and as a result people are becoming
...data-driven that literally like last month I was talking
to some executives from some fromcompany and they do...they have
retail stores and it's not like a website they have like physical retail stores and they were like
also if we if during this sales season if my store opens on
the east coast like by the time the time comes for the vest
post can I'm going to get some analytics so I can I can read a range
staff and the physical store and all that like wow really so basically like you want to
get the data from the registers as people are buying stuff sanded
into the cloud analyze it you have your data size people ahead of time...be
define some models which can be used put it into a biif and have your business
decision-makers look at it and call someone on the rest vesco so they can be can
...something physically wow that's impressive so basically it's also about like time to insight
and then again the ...the for thing is about like the type of the data is becoming is
not generated because it is...define schema and everything because
...is easy to when process downstream like all varying type of data is
generated like even in microsoft like when we go and analyze the data which is
coming from the support calls like that is literally the guy on the phone and
he's typing...as someone who's calling and saying like I have this issue like icon
research my password and this and that and like the guys capturing all of that
...there and they are they want to get that data maybe one hundred thousands of
calls and do machine learning on it so you have to would to organize it you have to analyze
...a different way and again the scale is big I want to...throw the
year how many calls have...in what was the primary reason I want to go
and classify it I want to label it I want to model it so the challenges are becoming really,
really interesting and that's where the whole big data
and the new set of technologies comes in so even primarily talk about
...so again because the data itself is a huge topic and there's a lot in it and
...results again
...of a decade back and ...how do...like I have to really, really, really,
really simplify this slide because if you go and look at some of the...slides out on the web it because
it's an open-source technology they talk about large of other stuff so,
there's a reason I like...
made it very simple are there are three things there is batch which I'm going to talk about there is no
...store which is h base I want to talk about and there's a streaming solution which is
stall and these are all the technologies that come under them
...hd insight which is the big data service on and
I will take one by one and give you an introduction and then I will show you in the code of what you can go and
do with that?
So, how as I said...is the aggregate offering what they do is that they take
...brought the...which has been done outside which is which is how do it's not that my
...is not contributing their microsoft another big
enterprises your contributing but they all go back into the into the main trunks everyone else
...benefit this has a lot like in terms of the velocity
...which you can develop and the number of the reviews that you get on the
...itself like this has been amazing for us to go and take a back on this
open-source...platform so some of the
can like question that come to me is like so,
this is how do like if I go to the apache trunk how's that different than what I get on
...there's a lot of differences one is that there's not change like we don't change the
...if you add something we added back into the trunk but the key
things are that it is fully managed so I don't know like how many people have
...about big data like pick any book from...anywhere like first each represent how
...set of your cluster because it is so hard to
set of these clusters so the first thing you will get is that and...you go in and you say I want I want
...I one-star my one how do and I want to five hundred more cluster and
...in fifteen minutes you have a five hundred node cluster all set of for you and it's
not just scripts because even if a single node goes down it is a
us who will wake up and fix it for you so it is fully manage service so we provide
you nsa lay-offs ninety nine-point nine up
percent up time so you don't have to go and worry so these are the
two big points which people don't understand if they just say this is an open-source thing which
we are offering the third thing is that the understand our customers we understand
...more...customers...enterprises we know that many of those have
of spender lies building applicationsin dot net and as, you know,
most of these open-source technology...support dot net or they don't have any binding into the into
the visual studio...for the development environment and that's...we go in and
we really invest...invest in the productivity we want to make sure that people
who are who have been familiar with microsoft tools with gs and others they can go in
the use these you want to make sure that if you are writing your next
in js application or your for your windows phone or for your for tablet you can
go and connected these technologies and all the bindings that api and dot net
libraries are idea for you to build but at the same time if you want to be the one who
...in scholar and enclosure and java like...all work as well
actually like the even do some work to make that one easy as...so that is like the
key...prob that we provided that is what like
...ideas a-z site is the big data offering on
as so you can go and build your applications on top of on top of these clusters?
So, three slides the last two slides one for each of the first one is five of
...talk about...is a query language literally you goal of
...you go in and you start putting your data and agile very typical scenario I'm
talking about either your data is just is born in the cloud...your data
is being generated from your io devices or somewhere and you throw it into the cloud
...they basically one example is like a while one of the companies like just giving...
are there you...based company they do for charities and all of that they
did an awesome project they took all of their data put it in the cloud and
they build a...in...off like how people are related and,
what are the...what are the places...give charities in which organizations and in
this case like they were able to come up with this very interesting insights and they even have a case studies so
...you are being...google for it just giving yean site you will find the case study so
very interesting stuff people have done with it so the basic concept is that the
high of is a very powerful query language ...can create a table and when I say create
a table like the one difference you see is that in the big data into
...the old-style like basically you define the schema first and then you
write it in the...data world you right first and then you define the schema and that
sleight change changes the...you handle with data because once
venue are storing the data you don't need to worry about what I will...do with it
...be the questions I will ask how...relations should be defining anything like all you do
...mutually...storing your of the cst files or your text files
...your laws or the streams...coming from diode you just keep the storing that?
And, then when the time...you want to go and do something you define the table and then you
...writing your kuwaitis the second one is age
...is bases and, also store it gives you a really,
really, really fast read and write access like, for example,...facebook, facebook messaging
...it's built on each base like millions of people are going in there and they will
...look at the messages will...they will righted the redid
...uses a lot in age base for their stuff so it's a really,
really powerful store that you can go and
...your data and then build application on top of it and this is one of the stores that
people use today to build the application the last one is strong its
user for streaming the one thing which I want really of one beautiful classes the is the
...box and, the thing which is in there is...topology...
...you will hear a lot
...the next forty-five minutes is topology and apologies made of
spouting...so that's what it shows it's seems like the water's coming into the
actually the data is coming in so you write...spout which is a connector so you go and you connect to
a source what is your source data coming from your device coming from your
...coming from your computer...from your phone coming from
the twitter stream anything that is your spouse so basically you're
spouse available for many of the things which are out there and then you do your business operations
I want...doing of...in function I want...in...I want to...redid from
...age base anything and those are the...so the reason I'm spending an extra minute on it is like
...you build application we will be doing a lot so let me go and, a spout for this data
source or...will go and add this...which does this thing and then together they
...topology ok so just...talk about this one of the one of the scenarios
...are working very closely with one of the big automobiles in
us and later this year they...with one of the brands...they
have built a really, really interesting disconnected carson...and again,
this is much simplified than what it is there but, the idea is similar we're like the
...keep sending data and you can do a lot of interesting scenarios including the
preventive...maintenance so they look at the data coming from the
sensors the outside temperature how the current has been behaving...they have already loaded
lot-of their data in the store so they do a join so it's like when was this
car came in for the last check-up and all of that so basically based on that they have
...a very nice end-to-end
...scenario and in terms of the technologies the
...the one which data game-like agile provides you alteration so you can slapping and...
about different type of stores and all of that is some of the one which I displayed here like
again, storm is the one which is the pipeline of how the data
slowing and then you can do multiple operation in india ok so
...of talking...things in mind big data has the capability to query to
...it has...also...which
...streaming pipeline which is which is called the storm and then in there you
build the topology is vcr...off the spouse
...ok so let's switch to demo?
Okay, so, I have a visual studio here I will startwith...with a new project.
in their you will notice that...in as part of the templates that get shipped are there is a
...site in there and what this allows you is that it gives you the
...you don't have to worry about the dependencies you don't even have to worry about like
...do I what is the interface that I need to add for my spout and
...it will give you an empty spouting...bold and
an empty topology which are connected so that is the advantage you get so one thing which I did was
actually I wanted that if someone wants to follow us along they can do it so every
code which I'm doing I have put it...online galley we hope to clean it up and also
ship it as part of the vs so if you go to the to the online one and then search
...here and then search for let's say hd
inside one-click...thank you?
So, you will get this the starter
...template the so...for this one and this one agnes and online...so you can all
get it what this does is that let me just call it?
Demo build.
So, this gives you the same scaffolding plus little more and what it does is that
also demanding brainstorming in terms of like up what is the demo we do in and,
it does the source of the stream does not make a huge difference and then you...
connect to some stream...just coming from your device...is coming from anywhere so
what we thought was that it would be interesting if we can pick if you connect...twitter because...that and
give-me continuous stream and then we can go and analyze it will be much more readable
then if I tell you that this...thing which is coming is from the device and trust me it
is real or something so this gives you more readable stuff that comes in so, as
a result what we have is remember the spouting...discussions so it has one spout and one
...if you click on the spout
basically it uses the I will build it so that it resolve the dependencies it uses the
treat I envy which is an object...by as it is one of the csharp libraries to go and
...like...like you can use it in your any dot net application there are many other
...libraries out there you can use any real quick I think that's highlights the our of when you're
building a csharp application of your connecting to a source and, you know, how to connect to it because you
built, you know, you...the worker role you build something already you can leverage that a lot of
that existing code and that knowledge you have right here in your in your topology yep so,
basically, yeah, so, you can pretty much use any library so if you are, for example,
you are writing to sql you can you...not in this algorithm...you use it so,
in there you come in and
...this library requires you to say what are the hash tags you are looking
for so in the template avi just...coffee and nhl you can change it
you can say like I'm looking for build two thousand and fifteen
and I can make some more variations of this I can say?
Build.
And, then this one as.
An looks good that's good okay so now it will go and look for these two
issues are coming in but it connects using my developer api that is the
one which I did not share...so you get your on us but I will go
and add...very quickly so you...quality it get your
cameras writing on it so we're here you go and see if
and close so, I put in my...developer key in there so now I can use that develop
...to google...to twitter.
There is nothing else so this pretty much is basically does next to each
which comes in it adds to the
q and then when it says next apple again this is a deeper topic in terms of in spout
...is one method which is the most critical which is next...and
...as soon as it has process one event it will automatically call next double for the
next one and it continuously keep doing it a very fast rate?
So, basically when this happens the big the one from the
...which is a local in memory and then send you the next one as I said there is this was the spout
then there is a...doesn't do anything other than that says this is the schema and it puts
...method in the addresses execute tweet and this is for you to go
...any business logic you can say filter out for...only english or do
there'slike whatever you want to...you do it will do it on every operation these are the two classes then this is
a topology the topology the one which binds or
stitches together the spouse in the...so?
Inherit right now you can see that there is one spout and there's one
...so to quickly go through it basically this
...takes like the name then it takes context which comes from the get
method then it says what is your schema and the schemas just the tweet
and that's it and then it says the parallelism and I have project one so that
...we are we were be unable to go and jump in and when detailed is
how the scale outings happen basically...whether you talk about storm
hb is how do they have many things in parallel which is about the
scalability which is about the fault tolerance all of this so
...you whether I write discord and analyze five
...or I analyze five million tweaks this code does not
change and all you have to do is maybe you increase the size of the cluster
and on that also I will show you in a second how you do it in the...so
with this much pretty much I can go and compile it and put it on my
...cluster and you will see the tweets but the problem is...see that reach...you
...front-end and eigenvalue that it is analyzing but, you can't see it so,
basically what they will do now is that you will quickly create
...and then we can connect the two sides and then go from there sounds good and
real quick and the second pull down here where the where the twitter bowl that's where I would put business
logics like by and other reference data that I want...maybe I have
...twitter handles and I had information my serum about them I would...I could join it in there and then
...to another downstream system okay all right so I'm going
to build the front-end so if I'm going to build this front-end traditionally
as a dot net developer I would want to use some sort of web
...technology to connect my...my front-end so since this is all in csharp my able to use signal
are yep that's a great one basically strong uses the
push mechanism so basically any application or anything
which are very you can push your stream of data is an ideal one like the recent riza our
...also allows that so you can also use our...you where you can...the data directly to
your dashboard all right so I've got visual studio and to make sure there's no magic going on
behind the scenes I'm...to do file new project right from here to do asp dot net app we'll call
it build twenty fifteen?
Avi demo.
And, I'm going to do
an empty whether api app and I'm not...in the cloud just yet and click on okay.
The reason I chose to do what api app is I'm going to just have
an index page that is going to connect a single our community
...smell page and then eventually we might connect to our
age base data stream and I'll do that through api and pull that into my front-end.
So,...this creates.
So, here's my basic build demo so the first thing since we're going to use signal
are is I'm going-to go ahead and in stall the signal our new get package
...install anyone know what it is...for bonus points.
Yes, whoever said that was right now yeah, so, it's a single are is
...that...are you can always do this through the gooey as well I just think that installs
little faster if you do it through the command-line hopefully it will do this.
There we go.
...afraid I'm going to type in a spell...wrong...some than my codes going to fail
...I have someone else's library right so we have then
stalwarts and song you can see its adding all...references for j query
and single are all that I need to use so I haven't had...
Do much yet?
What is done it gives me this nice read me that reminds me that I need to create a
owen startup class?
I'm going to use the our visual studio to write click on my projects.
And, go to add.
Is going to say hey you want to...owen startup class which I do call it startup?
And, right here it's...put app.
Dot...how many people here...use signal...before all right so you guys I'm glad I'm going to go through
this pretty quick...so right so now add-in index file.
All right we'll call this...storm.
I've got some snippets here to cheat so I'm just going to dragon my script references which
I'll go through so I'm you...to use when js to style thisalso going
to have my connection to j query to signal...and this is, you know,
the dynamic how that's created is a script here and then on...in the
...js control library cause I'm going to...js and my app logic
for this particular page will be stored in app js file that we will create all right
we'll come into the body so since I'm using when js I'm going to have all my app logic
...space called app so put that here.
And, I'm going to add in my well, that was already did...
edit toolbar so we have a nice toolbar at the top and it's just going to have a little header called
storm signal are and we can change that to be
...on demo right and then it's got a button that's a toggle button so many click it
...to recede tweets...could start my connection and I'll click it
...it so super simple that's our toolbar we're going to
display some the text of the tweets so we're going to have a tweet...template that just as an
h to tag that's going to be bound to the contents of the tweet dot text.
And, the last thing we need is a list
view to hold all those tweets so this is cool about when js obviously I
could've done this and angular I could users to j query doesn't matter what I do this in
...js I just telling my item data source...bind it to a variable called
app dot tweets which will be a list so...that go into my scripts.
That's our front-end.
Let's add-in javascript file called app.
And, here if I wanted I could use bauer and I could pull down a
when js starter but I've got it's just a few lines of code so a guy here got my
solving closed function that's got my
...called app that's what we called it and then a statement a
processes so within the app I've already coded up the definition which is pretty
straightforward it's got a tweets object the whole the list of tweets
...what bound to our list view and then I put in a couple code
...some code to kind of demo it before I connect
it lives I've got an interval id when I click the button I'm going to generate some fake tweets
the just says a new build tweet with the straying it's going to do this every second
so let's stop here intestine make sure that our app is running?
Share front-end is doing what we expect.
...maybe you should try ee, yeah.
We'll go with that all right so here's storm demo I
click live and hopefully I've got my new tweet so this
is what our front-end looks like it's not anything fancy but we built in what thirty seconds
so if I stop and...started clears...list and goes again so now let's connect
this to signal r so we already have our
startup class the next thing we need is a hub for signal are so
we'll go here again we knows what new get packages we've
...suggesting we have a single art class so I
will add that we'll call it storm hub because we're going to connect...storm.
So, this is where I now have my
storm this is where I will build the function that assad is going to put into the bolt to
send to us so let's call this probably show tweets.
And, let's take a few strings will take the tweet id and the tweets.
And, then ...come in here and we'll say show tweet to our clients.
And, we'll just pass in the same text.
now we've got our...server code that's going to connect with the...that is going to start sending our
front-end clients tweets...the last thing we need to do is wire that up in our javascript.
So, we'll come right here and sort of type...down I have it
right here so what is going to do is going to connect to a storm hub which is...our connection
...then going to should run here's the show tweet function we created which is
ads a tweet to our apps dot tweet list right...the same thing...test
code is doing so we'll get rid of our test code inhabit start our connection so we'll get rid of
that now our connection is started and we will stop it and sort of
...interval so now we no longer have some test data being generate every second it's
going-to be coming from our hub and we'll get rid of this down there.
So, just like that we should be able to deploy this to add here and have assad...data so to
should highlight again the visual studio tooling will...click on our project and
...publish and writer visual studio I can come in here click a new
websites...call let's?
Build twenty fifteen avi
demo see if that's available and it is...in the west us.
So, this is going to the edge portal creating
...the website a web server and the west united states and,
it once it creates a will download the publishing profile and we'll have publishable package of
...code and send it out here it is.
So, hopefully as developers maybe you've done this before...not the kind of
shows you how quickly you can use visual studio in the tools that measure provides to get
...just like we have html sites the web team is done a great job as well.
And, so.
Here we go up online is build twenty fifteen hd demo dot
edu websites net and once we connect assad starts connecting that to
our data we can all come here and we'll see it live...
great so...association of you have the front-end so we will use strong
and from strongly will go and...push these...streams to that and point.
So, the one thing now we need is another
...so remember I hope you have not forgotten so basically there was one spout reading from
...than one bolt that was pretty much not doing anything and then we need another
both that is a...it to the signal are so, again, this is
one of the once we just published online all you...you say op-ed new item.
And, in there if you go and search like my
...already...with this is the signal are both you can go and add this one.
And, now has added this both let me just move it under the
boats directory and if you go and look at it basically
what it does is that it takes the tweets which are coming in and how a
and which are coming is from the board which is which is behind this and then it pushes it
to the website where do I put the website and the hub name all
...of that is captured in the conflict file again it's a good design
...just put everything in there so if you go in there I will go and
add the website here?
Through the snippets.
So, basically it...for the website url and, the signal our hop
again I...hobbies the same you use the...I use the storm...is what I called it yes and
then so the site is...twenty fifteen.
Hd I demo.
Okay.
So, knowledge has the address now there's one thing missing I don't know
if anyone can remember we have not stitch this together as part of the topology
sly added and they're both but it is hanging up in the air so I have to put it as part
of my topology so I will go back to the topology and...
do another set...against the to save time I will just add this thing of
it says the...signal are
and added these for lines so basically it gives...name signal
our bolt and then it gives the get method it gives you the schema
and it says from there that we just coming and that we just coming from the previous
board so this is how it is stooges together the topology the
...just look for the name space.
Which is this one and I will added there?
Hopefully not should come file.
Yep, okay, so, again, just repeat what we did was we added another
...this...takes the data from coming from the from the spout into the
...and this is a signal are both...just needs an address
...just keep pushing everything that it is getting at the streams so.
Now if...go...compile this thing we can go and actually deploy
it to my big data storm cluster...did I get the
strong cluster again, I commuted beforehand because it takes fifteen minutes for the cluster to spin
up like how many people have actually seen the as your portal like either this one or the new one
...a great otherwise I would have one back to the slidesso, basically you can see new and then you can go
...inside and then you can take the type of the cluster you want this is the
...cluster I have two one is the hardest online let-me
...this thing and the other one is database one which I will use for other purposes
so I will go and deploy to this cluster if you go on the scale you can see right now it's a
...cluster but even if a whether it
...even if that apologies deployed or not I can literally
take this and go all the way here and I can go to any number of nodes right now I'm
...eighty-one because that's because of the...but if I if I want I can make it...order five hundred nodes
...once I ...in the demo then I go to email that how much money
...wasted then I don't do that so we'll keep it to for node so,
let's go back here and deploy so the other thing which we have done is that we have
made really easy from the visual studio to go and deploy into any of the
...or...clusters so if you goal here and rightly you will see the option since is
a is a strong topology that submit to the
...insights dom.
It will show me all the clusters that I have in my subscription because I have installed as
...that comes for visual should use
...you get two-point-five now I can go in I can deployed to the to
the staging cluster and isa submit.
At this point it will take that code and hopefully if I have not made
an error it will go and deployed in my
...as soon as it gets deployed it will
it will run and it will start reading the to each that are coming in it will look for the
...hash codes that the defined in over spout because
...the connector save look for all that which coming under this subject heading and then
it will give you it will send it to the next...and...ascended to the third...
is the signal...similarly say what have to do all I have to push it to a site and it will
push there seems like there was another one which...kill actually?
So, this is some old topology I will just skillet in
...while we're waiting for the topology
deploy if you're so inclined you can pull out your phone and write-up a tweet
with the hash tags either has tag build twenty fifteen or build fifteen or build
win but we all them just any of them and once we do that at all show
up live on the screen...is...address...twenty fifteen hci demo.
Demo dot as...websites dot net.
You can see we're getting tweets that are coming in now.
So,...basically irrespective of
...is this is the part ofstreaming twitter data is where's all planned it
moi all...bad because we wanted to see some smil so,
basically again like irrespective of what are the data is the key thing is that...you need
an api to connect whether you connect to the event of whether you connect to your device
you connect to another source in this case we chose to connect to the twitter so again the
...because...a little more interesting and then it is about how you build app by connecting
...together and then you use
various technologies of whether for storing or for displaying ok so let's do something
as right...make itlike deed...can we go and add to it,
yeah, so, we're receiving data from a stream but that's not very useful we can't do analysis on it we
can't review it later so why don't we start and use h
base and start storing this data age base yep let's do that so I will
go ahead so, again, this part is all we build it out as part of for deploying
...whole strom topology management is within the visual
...I can go and say let me guild...topology?
And, now...the...will stop coming to the website and v will
add the hbo and as...is saying what it gives you is that it gives you a persistent
storage most of the time who are people who are building streaming applications
...they do both batch and stream so they do streaming just like the you signal
...our by or any other life dashboard but at the same time they don't want to lose the data
which is coming in they want to store the data that is used for brand
analysis for historical data for machine learning for deeper analysis of your data and this
dumb is like has become very common which is called the lambda architecture them lend architecture is
very splits the stream for real-time and it also sources in batch so what we will do
that we will go and use nh basic...and put all these trees that are coming in into the
...as well as continue to get it on our live dashboard.
So, what I will do is that of coming back to
over application I will go here and now add another
...and this time it will be the
hbo right board so I add new item and again all of these are and,
not in vs but online so if you click on the online and then search for it you should be able to
see these ones?
As I will say that ...bolt.
And, let me just move it under here.
And, again, same standard process we will if you want to go and modify something in
...we can go and modify that this is a very general-purpose
...is...we did a few modification so that the number of lines we
have digest to match the schema
...we can avoid those things but in general this is a very john urbanization
...boarded...you have to just give the address of your
...base and the schema you want to go in the table name and if you go
into it before I do that let me go in actually...connected to my age base...so this is my age
base cluster and again this is the topic I'm not going to...which is like
...a...has a has a shel where you can say show me the tables show me the
...show me everything which is in there so, for example, you can go ahead and you can say
list and...show you all the tables and right now there is no table india so
...starting with an empty age base cluster...look up a come back to advanced once
the once the data xr to come in and...table which is created.
So, again,
this similar process which we did we will go to theto the conflict file and
...the information about our were ...cluster so in
...the add the...the name of the...
cluster username password the column name as well as the schema which I
want to...in define and this is the one which will be picked up by this board so now
if you remember the last thing is that we have to stitched to the topology but otherwise it is just a free-floating
...so I come here I have to the my one and then similarly what I
see is that the name the get method of what is the schemaand,
from where does it get the data.
I added those things so it's the same eigen define the name...the get method I
define the schema in this case the schema is not that much useful because this
board is the lost in the...not sending any there so I could
...this part in it will not make a difference and then from there does it get the data it gets
the data from the from this board which is that reachable so?
So, now with these three changes if I go and again, build my.
My project.
Again,...the redeployment I should be able to see the data
matches coming...now stored as a as part of my age base.
So, now we can again goal here two-minus cluster.
The storm cluster.
And, right now you can see there's no topology because,
because the last one so as soon as this comes up you will start again seeing
...the tweets flowing through it and the number the number of to is that are
process act again like some of the details region go in but
there's lot of somebody that comes displayed as part of the topology when you go and run it.
Now if I go and open the
...and had the back-end or you just see if it search straining,
yeah, so, it will go to just us artistry...here again.
And, as some
...comes in I can go and...that is also going into the age base.
Let me go and see.
So, you can see there is still zero in here.
I don't know what website are.
It's our build twenty fifteen hd demo.
Ok, so, now basically again this was the party had already seen but now if you go into the
age base and now if you say list you should see the table which is the
trick-or-treat underscore dvr table and all that was that are coming on the screen are also being
saved here so if you say let's say right now we don't have that many so
...can even do a scan which will go in print all of them.
So, this is go...printing all...are in there so now all
the tweets are coming on the signal are and they're also going into the
...base and getting persisted and now this is a
very powerful store you can go and do anything with it you can go and build
...a lot of different type of applications so
this one like do you want to go and build something on top of it like what's,
what's your plan...so what we'll do now is we'll build and I'll show you how you would take
and connect that to api comptroller so you can start pulling in the data through a restful api
...ahead and switch over?
All right so we're seeing my screen so it's utc time right now is two thirteen am
I want remember that because that's when we started this job so when we view our
api control review the tweets...pulled back the first...be around to twelve in the
mornings restoring them on the server and utc time so let's go ahead and go individual studio.
And, the first thing like with single are will want to do is
install there's a new get package to the csharp library to connect
h base so we'll install that and that's install.
Package microsoft dot age base dot client.
So, this is the csharp the csharp client that connects to the age based apis
so you can insert data and you can pull down data and this is the same
...library that we had in a...code invisible
so now that we've got that installed we can keep going on so we've installed the
new get package the next thing we should probably do is create a web
...and api comptroller for receiving this service will come in
will create a new scaffolding item for a web empty what api controller.
And, we'll call it tweets api.
So, as a saddam hussein is the data is stored...h base but age
bases schema less so he define the schema as he was writing it and if we if we would have seen
...he was doing as you...youencoding all of the data into a
...array and storing that so what we'll have to do is define
our model and then do the same thing take it from a biter
...into our model so I'm going-to go ahead and add-in a model that is the same
as the model that assad used so this is where it within the same solution you
could reference the other ones but otherwise you would have the to duplicate this code so we'll call it tweet?
And, the model I have is right here so there's a model it's got the id the
string the idea of the tweet represented a...got created at the
...of the tweet and other characters or other data that assad
is saving for that the other thing that we should add...we're here is an ad
...existing item
...item is all on get hub and we'll provide the link here at the end of the demo but,
what it's the age base reader class so there's this class is what connects to rh
base cluster and then does the does the scan on the
apis and retrieves back the data so that's where I was saying it's going to do a scan and it's going to
...back all the information and we're going to take it from a wide array and put it into a straying or
...integer a daytime whatever we're storing it
from so this is what also enables the api...go really fast so it saying
that we are missing the name space for the tweet that we created so let's go ahead and add-in
are using statement for that and this is good so now we can wire up
Our web comptroller api again this code will share
is all on is all on get hub so we'll pose that link?
At the end here so I'm just going to add in our name space again for our...so that we've got the
age base reader I don't know why tweet...pull...do the same.
...and it's we need to add-in a...
All right so now we've got our wedding api that's connecting to h...it's doing
a scan and it's going to return the data as a json object and, restful
service so the last thing...to do is add-in rh base.
Connection information so that
I can connect so I have that saved again it's the same is assad had
...connecting to his cluster with his name password in the table that we want to retrieved from
some save this and now if I run as locally.
I can run this locally because the data is connecting to the to the clouds I can
deploy this and I would work and if I try and run this locally hit live it's not going to
work as the tweets aren't coming here but I can show you the api comptroller and,
I can deploy it to the clouds all-clear this might be a little faster so we'll see.
Well, that's...and paste in the url so it's connecting this is, you know,
what api routing so it's going to my api called tweets api it's got
the topic and then a time...the time that you want to get tweets from so that we can scan
are table maybe we want to jump to our we want to go back in time and
how many do we want and the one thing that I saw side do is our topic isn't
...general...do that so by hit this?
We should see tweets starting around the to twelve am
...and here we go so the first one was put in
...twelve and twenty seven seconds so
now this is api is going through and
its pulling down the data that assad is storing...base so if I was to come in here and,
...only want ten this will then come down and filter my list
...ten I can change my date and
time if I want to jump into something more recent I can come in here and put
in my time and I want to go to the...is it now so maybe
two eighteen and, hit this so now we'll jump.
All right I don't know the time syntax to get it to go to the actual time but when you
connect adding url encoded it-would pull down in jumped into the next
the next set so this is kind of a very generic example of we're taking
tweet were archiving them or saving them but some of the business use case you can see
ismaybe you are the build keynote,
for example, we've got build going on and you want to archive all of the keynote all the tweets that are coming in
...the keynote so that you can run analysis and run sentiment and understand what was the most
tweet what time period where the most treated was it when we announced the visual studio code was it
when it...showed how low...right so you could go and you could archive and
start doing analysis and say okay which features was everyone more excited about and one thing that
I thought of as we're doing this demo is I often don't
watch live tv so I didn't get a chance to watch the keno
...actually flying and I'm a...so I sometimes like to watch the
...tweets but I can't do that if I
fdr so what we created we kind of package this up a little bit more and we created
data dvr dot com so if you this is the code that will share on get...is
...project so if you go to data
...dot com I we just did a few topics I like the any I'm a huge
...gel fan so I got my play-off we're going on for the black
...as we got nhl topics being monitored we've got build and we've got
gamma drones so if we click on build we can see this is during the keno right around the
time we announced the...robot came out so we can
help play and this is going to start showing all those tweets that were happening at
one-thirty right so we kinda took this and made a consumer use case of
it but the real business use case of archiving these tweets might be that
we are doing sentence sentiment analysis were seeing what most people are excited about so, you know,
big data can have multiple facets of areas when you want to know and answer different problems
...exactly like basically...tim said like basically this is initially like you can go to either that
...like...keynote and then you open this on the side and then
...the as if it happened at that time and...to reading about it and,
it is exactly using the same topology like this is...policy that we finished
building is using the stream version and it is using the cash version and
...app is sitting where it allows both you if you take the time then it will go...base and
pick-up from the cache version if you will see...live at this point so literally now
if likes anyone of you treat it will go
ahead and show it right away so this is that we that is coming in like if someone from the
room to each type raise your hand and, you can...one of these hash tags
...when we made thison sunday we forgot that build twenty fifty
...probably the more popular tweet so it's only as build microsoft build
when so it would have to be one of those tweet if you want appear on-screen but, yeah.
Anyone tweets and appears on screen raise your hand
...funder...out but anyways that's great so basically the one
...which I want to ensure and then we can have two and a ...you have all these like
...seven minutes is the
...so basically let me switch the machine?
Now we got some from greece streaming online how nice, yeah.
Okay, so.
So, basically the...the...pieces the...pieces recovered is
...and...the third one which I will talk about is the high...again like majority...people who are
right now using I do they are using...deposit is a very powerful query language either
...use big or some other query language to cleanse their data modify join data and
then they have the high squeeze go against it and, do all
sort of interesting stuff on top of it so ...me connect to the same cluster which is the
...staging cluster and I will say I will write
...query so, these are the odds of one
...which I've taken in this case is that high of works when you have the data in the
...fs energy-efficient the file system and in case of casual
or that means as long as your data is in the blob store you can you have for that
...api on top of its you can write height so literally anyone out there
who's data is in agile blob can go and ria star writing
highs queries by spinning up and a-z site cluster in this case
...I build the topology I could have sure I could have chosen to take all that
...are coming in and rather than storing...hbo
story directly into the blob store but since I did not do it I just want to show it the
hives what...do is that you can still create a...of table on top of on top of
...base and this is through the survey which is the extensibility nh base with
...lets you use the civilization dc analyzer and
...lies that does that so basically if you if you if you're not doing on
age base but you're just directly doing it on the blob then all you do is use a
create table and then give the schema right now I have to say directional table so now
I'll give you an example of the hives and what people can do is like you can do really,
really deep operations and then is...us analysis
or the machine learning part of the to give you a quick example what I'll do is like I will take all that
...use that are in this cluster and this cluster I don't have many like basically if I
do the count right now because this is the one which we just set up?
Basically the I'll just have...we just started this one but I will go and look at these
one thirty-five queries and I will say...and, gramm and
...is like people go and see which to words or...of the
most commonly together and then you can say show me the top ten
grams of something so basically there is a function...can say...the...grams.
And, what it takes is the is the token and,
in this case I don't have the tokens all I have is the is this is
the strings are the or that...that are coming in so I have
the text instead as what I will do is that I will say?
Make it lower.
And, then I will to organize it and there is a function for that as well.
So, now it is to organised and then I can say am I looking
at diagrams...or...or force so I'm looking at ...let's
see the bigram and I want to look at the top them.
And, then I can...as and...from and the from is the table name which
in this case is the is that we table and then I just
a select annals of...writing my query select and
grams and now what will happen is just it'll just print the one
big line of like the...that comes out so I want to just printed out on each
separate line so I can use another function which says the
explode which makes it on a separate line.
And, hopefully if I type everything correctly now what I'm doing is I'm taking
...text from the
...making it lower-case then I'm make to...it then I'm doing the
n gramm's looking for the bigram then I'm exploding it so that every shows up in
a separate line now from visual studio I can since I'm connected to measure
cong I can say submit and it will go and submit this query
and again, highly is still so basically if you are used to sequel yup,
yeah, like you have to wait a minute but, again,
it's nobody's powerful...this thing on those one hundred thirty five degrees or
...righted on a billion art which doesn't matter like...just go
and perform and get me the results so here you can see the job status.
So, once it finishes we can go and look, at the results and it'll show you as I said like the
top ten and gramm's on a separate lines so basically hopefully this
guy as I said like the...a lot of topics...are covering here big data how you build
application...stop-off it what other type of things you can go into how you build your stormed apologies
use h base and then like a ten-minute ten seconds into the high but,
that's pretty much what we wanted to cover update take you to a journey
off like taking one data source and build some interesting app out
of it as tim said like most of the stuff we showed you is already out there you can go
to data dvr dot com right now you can play with it like this if
...did it and deployed on sunday evening around seven so at least during
that last for days you can go to any time and pick the topic and it will show you the
tweets as if they are happening right now...is there the
...sense...I use their all online soI hope this was useful for
you if you have questions we...just two more minutes lunch but this wide up...with the thank you?